nbaa.org 2017-01-29

# NBAA Website Privacy Policy | NBAA - National Business Aviation Association

Updated May 1, 2013

The National Business Aviation Association, Inc. (NBAA) respects the privacy of its Members and other visitors to its website, NBAA.org. NBAA is committed to maintaining your privacy and providing you with options regarding the use of your Personal Information. This Privacy Policy describes NBAA's current association policy on how we use Personal Information that is provided to NBAA through NBAA.org. 

Please review the entire Privacy Policy carefully. By continuing to use NBAA.org, or by providing NBAA with your Personal Information, you consent to this Privacy Policy. If you have questions about this Privacy Policy or the Personal Information we may have on file and how we use it, please contact NBAA at (202) 783-9000 or email [info@nbaa.org](mailto:info@nbaa.org).

## Changes to This Privacy Policy

On occasion NBAA may revise this Privacy Policy to reflect changes in the law, NBAA's association practices or features on NBAA.org. If any of these changes impact the way we collect or use your Personal Information, those changes will be posted on this Privacy Policy and the effective date will be noted. Therefore, you should review the Privacy Policy periodically to remain aware of NBAA's current policies and practices.

## Collection of Personal Information

This Privacy Policy covers Personal Information, which includes your name, mailing address, email address and telephone number, and may also include additional information provided to NBAA, such as your credit card details. Some Personal Information may be provided to NBAA by those individuals who manage your company’s Membership or register you for NBAA events.

### From General NBAA.org Visitors

NBAA does not collect any Personal Information from visitors browsing NBAA.org unless they voluntarily submit information through online forms requesting additional information.

### From NBAA Members, Event Registrants and Other Customers

Personal Information may be collected when visitors apply for Membership through the online application, renew their Membership, edit their profile at My NBAA Profile or apply to exhibit at or sponsor an NBAA event. 

To gain access to the Members-only areas of NBAA.org, Members are asked to register for a website password and provide Personal Information related to their company's Membership. The website log in process sets cookies which can allow NBAA to track, for a single session, what pages are viewed by this visitor, as well as network and browser information specific to that individual visitor. This information is not disclosed outside of NBAA, and is used to improve the content and performance of NBAA.org or for security purposes.

Some Personal Information, such as name, mailing address, email address and telephone number, is collected during the event registration process and for online orders of publications and other NBAA products and services. This information is used to facilitate the registration or transaction.

Additionally, for some email messages sent in HTML format by NBAA to Members, event registrants and other customers, NBAA will collect specific information regarding what the recipient does with that email. For those email messages, NBAA or its service providers can track whether a recipient opens the message and subsequently clicks through to links provided in the message. NBAA may use this information to enhance its products and the distribution of those products to its Members. This information is not sold or disclosed outside of NBAA in any other manner.

### From Participants in NBAA Sweepstakes or Surveys

NBAA may, from time to time, collect additional Personal Information on our website, such as in connection with sweepstakes or Member surveys. Information collected will be handled in accordance with this Privacy Policy unless we notify you differently at the time of collection. If you do not wish to share such Personal Information, you may always decline to participate.

## Use of Collected Personal Information

NBAA uses information voluntarily submitted by Members and other customers in a variety of ways listed below. If you do not want your information used in these ways, you may follow the instructions below or choose not to submit your Personal Information to NBAA, as appropriate.

NBAA will not use your Personal Information for purposes that are different than those detailed below, unless we ask your permission to do so. 

### Product Offers, Legislative/Regulatory/Policy Updates and Other Announcements 

NBAA uses names, mailing addresses, phone numbers and email addresses to communicate product and service offers or important legislative, regulatory and policy or informational updates that we think may be of interest to you. ****

### Developing NBAA Products and Services 

NBAA uses data collected to improve its website content; to respond to visitors' interests, needs and preferences; and to develop new products and services.

### Disclosure Within NBAA and to NBAA Partners

NBAA shares Personal Information with NBAA employees, agents, contractors and other partners who have a legitimate business need for such information or perform services on behalf of NBAA, such as fulfilling orders, processing credit card transactions or assisting NBAA with any other allowable purpose.  
NBAA shares limited information, such as name, mailing address, and telephone number, with NBAA Affinity Partners who offer valuable services to NBAA Members (e.g. Workers’ Compensation Program, Business Aviation Jobs Board). NBAA Affinity Partners are not permitted to sell, rent, or share NBAA Member information with any other companies or partners. The only authorized use of our Member mailing address and phone numbers is in regards to offers directly related to the services our NBAA affinity partners are providing to NBAA. NBAA Affinity Partners may not contact you for any other reason or without NBAA’s knowledge. NBAA and our Affinity Partners also occasionally contract telemarketing firms to make calls on our behalf about our products and services, however those companies are also permitted to only use our Members’ phone numbers for the specific NBAA campaign that they have been hired to execute.

### NBAA Member Directory and Other Rosters

NBAA makes individual contact information for employees of NBAA Member Companies available to other Members through the password-protected, Members-only online [Member Directory](http://www.nbaa.org/directory) and to all NBAA.org visitors through the Products & Services Directory. NBAA Member Representatives may choose to have their companies excluded from these directories by updating their Organization Profile in [My NBAA Profile](http://www.nbaa.org/mynbaa) or by contacting NBAA Member Services at [membership@nbaa.org](mailto:membership@nbaa.org) or (202) 783-9000. Individuals may choose not to be included in these directories, even if their companies are listed, by contacting NBAA Member Services at [membership@nbaa.org](mailto:membership@nbaa.org) or (202) 783-9000.

NBAA also makes available on NBAA.org limited Personal Information from those individuals who serve on NBAA’s voluntary committees, have achieved the Certified Aviation Manager (CAM) credential or participate in similar programs with NBAA. The NBAA staff liaison for each committee or program can provide available options for excluding your Personal Information.

### NBAA Event Rosters

NBAA may provide attendee rosters for NBAA Events to other attendees, NBAA Committees and event sponsors. Rosters may include names, job titles, mailing addresses and telephone numbers. **Email addresses are not included on attendee rosters.**

### NBAA Air Mail

Individuals at NBAA Member companies may choose to participate in Air Mail, NBAA's series of web-based forums and email discussion lists. By posting to Air Mail, either by email or through NBAA.org, Air Mail participants will share their name and email address with other participants via Air Mail Listserv, and with non-participating NBAA Members through the web-based Air Mail Forums. If you do not want to share this information, you should not participate in Air Mail. Air Mail participants must follow the [Air Mail rules](http://www.nbaa.org/airmail/rules/). To benefit all NBAA Members, Members violating these rules may be unsubscribed from Air Mail by NBAA at any time.

### Member Mailing List Rental

NBAA Members tend to turn to fellow Members for the vendors and suppliers they need to make their businesses and flight operations more successful. To help facilitate that process, NBAA makes its Membership mailing list available for rental. For more information, visit the [NBAA Member Mailing List Rental page](http://www.nbaa.org/about/advertising/mailing-lists/). Personal Information included in such lists may include name, mailing address, and telephone number. **Email addresses will not be included on rented Membership mailing lists.**

Individuals may choose to have their information excluded from these lists provided to third parties by updating their Communications Preferences in [My NBAA Profile](http://www.nbaa.org/mynbaa) or by contacting NBAA Member Services at [membership@nbaa.org](mailto:membership@nbaa.org) or (202) 783-9000.

### Credit Card Account Information

NBAA does not disclose your credit card account information to anyone other than the credit card company that validates the charge for processing purposes. However, limited credit card information (such as the cardholder’s name and the last four digits of the card number) may be displayed on receipts or statements generated for you or your company. For their own personal security and privacy, NBAA encourages Members to use our secure website to communicate credit card information to NBAA. 

### Website Advertising

Personal Information may be used for targeting website display ads based upon NBAA Member category, company industry type, geographic region, job responsibility and other demographic information. This information may be saved in cookie files which will persist across multiple browsing sessions.

### Legal Authorities

NBAA may disclose Personal Information to third parties when we believe it is necessary in order to protect NBAA's legal rights; to protect the interests of Members and the business aviation community; to protect the safety and security of visitors to NBAA.org; to protect against fraud or for risk management purposes; or to comply with law or legal process.

## Security of Your Personal Information

NBAA uses reasonable measures to safeguard Personal Information in its possession against loss, theft or unauthorized use, disclosure or modification. In addition, NBAA uses reasonable methods to make sure Personal Information is accurate, up-to-date, and appropriately complete.

## Links to Other Websites

NBAA.org includes links to and advertisements for other third-party websites. NBAA takes no responsibility for the content or information contained on those sites. These websites may have their own distinct privacy policies or no posted policies at all, and may use your Personal Information in ways not permitted by the NBAA Website Privacy Policy. NBAA encourages you **** to review the privacy policies of any site before providing your Personal Information to them.

## Collection and Use of Non-Personal Information

NBAA may also collect information that does not identify a specific person (“Non-Personal Information”) from website visitors. This information may be collected by or shared with third-party vendors and partners, such as Google. The other provisions of this policy do not apply to such information, unless it is combined with Personal Information. NBAA and its partners may use cookies and other technologies to automatically collect Non-Personal Information, such as location, time zone, IP address, browser type, pages viewed, referral sources and frequency of visits. This information is used by NBAA to improve NBAA.org, track usage, market products and services, and for security purposes.

NBAA may use tools, such as Google Analytics for Display Advertising and Remarketing with Google Analytics. These tools allow NBAA to promote our products and services to website visitors after they have visited the NBAA website. You may opt out of Google Analytics for Display Advertising by visiting the [Google Ads Preferences Manager](http://www.google.com/privacy_ads.html). You may also install the [Google Analytics opt-out browser add-on](http://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout).

## Access to Your Personal Information and Choices Regarding Use

NBAA Members may update Personal Information and communications preferences at any time by logging into My NBAA Profile at [www.nbaa.org/mynbaa](http://www.nbaa.org/mynbaa) or by contacting NBAA Member Services at [membership@nbaa.org](mailto:membership@nbaa.org) or (202) 783-9000. When notified, NBAA will take reasonable steps to correct any Personal Information that is identified as incorrect.
